Guide to the Ella Tilles Falk Papers 1919-1923
University of Chicago Library
Falk, Ella Tilles. Papers
1919-1923
4 linear feet (3 boxes)
Hanna Holborn Gray Special Collections Research Center University of Chicago Library 1100 East 57th Street Chicago, Illinois 60637 U.S.A.
Ella Tilles Falk attended the University of Chicago as an undergraduate from 1919 to 1923. The collection contains a scrapbook documenting her undergraduate life, and includes event programs and tickets, clippings, photographs, notes from friends, party place cards, and other ephemera. With the exception of one letter, material in the collection dates from 1919 to 1923.
Information on Use
Access
The collection is open for research.
Biographical Note
Ella Tilles Falk was born in 1902 to a family of Polish Jews in Fort Smith, Arkansas. Her parents were George and Lillian Tilles. In 1919 she entered the University of Chicago, graduating in 1923 from the College of Commerce and Administration. While at the University, she was vice-president of the Southern Club, active in the WAA, and served on the staff of the Commerce and Administration Magazine.
In October of 1923 Ella married John Allfree, also a University of Chicago alumnus, in Fort Smith, Arkansas. She later married George Falk, an insurance agent. Falk lived in Fort Smith until her death on April 21, 1999. An avid doll collector, she left her collection to the Fort Smith Museum of History.
Scope Note
This collection consists of a scrapbook compiled by Ella Tilles while an undergraduate at the University of Chicago. Much of the material was stuffed loosely into the scrapbook and has been foldered separately. Because very little of it can be dated precisely, the contents have been grouped and arranged alphabetically (i.e., “Bridge Tally Cards,” “Blackfriars Program,” “Poems,” etc.). The collection includes personal items, such as photographs, notes, and drawings from friends, as well as mementos such as dance cards, ticket stubs, and event programs. Among the more charming items in the collection are a number of small party place cards and other party decorations (including an articulated paperboard skeleton), and a folder of Valentine cards.
The scrapbook itself is listed first in the inventory, followed by the loose items.
Related Resources
Browse finding aids by topic.
University of Chicago Scrapbooks. Collection
Lunde Family. Papers
Jameson, Vesta. Papers
John H. Roser. Papers
University of Chicago. Student Papers and Ephemera. Collection
Subject Headings
University of Chicago – History; University of Chicago – Students
INVENTORY
- Scrapbook, 1919-1923 (Box 1)
- Blackfriars Program: "Anybody's Girl," 1922 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Bridge Tally Cards, circa 1919-1923 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Clippings, circa 1919-1923 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Clothespin Dolls, Party Decorations, circa 1919-1923 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Dance Cards, circa 1919-1923 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Drawings, circa 1919-1923 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Event Invitations, 1920-1921 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Event Tags, circa 1919-1923 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Family Correspondence, 1919-1929 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Flyer – Alumni Day Circus, circa 1919-1923 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Greeting and Calling Cards, circa 1919-1923 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Gunther: "The Higher Learning in America," 1922 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Miscellaneous Ephemera, circa 1919-1923 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Miscellaneous Objects, circa 1919-1923 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Notes and Messages, Stationery Monograms, circa 1919-1923 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Photographs, circa 1919-1923 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Place cards, circa 1919-1923 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Poems – Various Authors, circa 1919-1923 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Program and Songbook – Orpheum Circuit, 1921 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Programs and Event Flyers, Non-University of Chicago, circa 1919-1923 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Programs – Federation of University Women Events, circa 1919-1923 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Programs -- University of Chicago Events, circa 1919-1923 (Box 2, Folder 22)
- The Prom Maroon, 1921 (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Tickets and Receipts, circa 1919-1923 (Box 2, Folder 24)
- University of Chicago Postcards, circa 1919-1923 (Box 2, Folder 25)
- Valentines, circa 1919-1923 (Box 2, Folder 26)
- Y.W.C.A Event Programs, Signature List, circa 1920-1921 (Box 2, Folder 27)
- University of Chicago Maroon, News Clippings and Ticker, 1921-1923, undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Paper Skeleton, circa 1919-1923 (Box 3, Folder 2)